

Simon Kerle Software Engineer

0412 139 846 s.kerle@gmail.com Glebe, NSW 2037



I am a full stack developer and consultant with more than 18 years of experience across a varied range of technologies. I've had the pleasure to be part of solving business challenges and generating revenue for several industries such as property, health, online dating, and accounting. I am experienced in agile ways of working including Extreme Programming (XP) and Scrum, combined with a dev-ops model. As well as delivering successful products, I am experienced at coaching and leading teams of software engineers.

Java Spring Spring boot Hibernate

## Work history

VMware Tanzu Labs

Senior Software Engineer

Nov 2021 - Jul 2024 Sydney

Frontend React Angular **Typescript** CSS

C#



Tanzu Labs is a consultancy that embeds in customer businesses and builds teams within the client organisation around XP, pair programming, and TDD. This is a unique structure whereby we not only deliver products for customers, but do it alongside existing or new client teams and coach them in effective agile practices while building their product and team simultaneously.

**DotNet Core** Entity Framework

\_\_\_\_

I worked with a client on several streams in an effort to modernise a legacy application suite, starting three from scratch. We helped them grow from a team with only a few engineers to a team of over 20 while modernising their existing internal booking system and updating their development processes from bureaucracy heavy, high defect, and IT driven to business driven agile process with a rapid turnaround from backlog to release and low defect rate.

Mobile React Native

Database

Postgres

Oracle MSSQL

Shell

Bash

Kafka



Some highlights are:

- I led engineering on 3 streams of work and contributed to two others
- Switched between streams regularly and was able to rapidly understand the systems involved and provide engineering leadership
- Mentored client and consultancy team members in XP, pair programming, and TDD
- Built and maintained Kubernetes Helm charts
- Built a patient search API using ElasticSearch with ETL from legacy InterSystems Cache database
- Facilitated full team engineering shareback meetings
- Interviewed engineering hires
- Provided expertise on issues and solutions to product management and design
- Provided advice to client management on the progress of the team
- Provided feedback to my consultancy management on the progress of the team and the relationship with the client
- Worked closely with offshore and out of state teammates on a daily basis
- Scoped and estimated work for prospective clients

Messaging RabbitMQ

Automation



Cloud Kubernetes Docker Cloud Foundry **AWS GCS** 



CI/CD Gitlab Azure Pipelines **DevOps** 

 Corelogic

Apr 2017 - Nov 2021 Senior Software Engineer Sydney

Corelogic offers market property valuations and tracking but also develops specific real estate valuation systems for major real estate market stakeholders. Software support and design is key to decision making information, macro and micro economic policies and domestic customers information. Systems and tools need to be accurate, timely and responsive to changing information demands. In this context, my role was to develop products from the front end, back ends, and APIs, estimating projects, and delivering reliable systems in tight deadlines. I was responsible for building and maintaining products and helping the team produce quality, reliable code. I've worked in large and small teams building React mobile apps and websites, and Spring Boot based API services. Highlights include:

- Fast tracked in a few months a React Native app for a large bank client, that had close to full test coverage and no major issues on release
- Built a product producing generic and ad-hoc reports for Real Estate agents to use when talking with either buyers or sellers

- Built a product that produced valuation reports for residential properties
- Built an API product to manage the process of ordering valuations and managing them as they progress through various internal and external systems
- Built various microservices that collect and provide access to property data
- Worked with offshore teams in the Philippines on greenfield projects and handed over products that had reached maturity
- Provided engineering expertise to product managers and designers to find appropriate solutions
- Used my expertise to coach team members through a combination of pair programming, code reviews, and one on one mentoring discussions
- Using observability tools such as Splunk and tracing tools to understand and resolve issues affecting production
- Optimised the performance of all systems from the client application to the server and database

RSVP.com.au

Oct 2008 - Mar 2017

Senior Developer

Sydney

Worked on a team of 5 developers in a business of around 20 people building and maintaining a dating website built on Spring, Struts, JSP, and using JQuery for light interactivity on the front end. At the time, RSVP was the largest dating site in the country. Due to high traffic with 20 - 60k nightly users, work was often focused on performance and reliability under heavy load. In this role I built new features, worked with the product team to propose solutions and testers to validate and improve them, and maintained an aging code base. I also helped train team members in our code base and in growing their skill as effective developers capable of building solid, reliable, and performant code.

## **Business Information Services**

Mar 2006 - Oct 2008

Web Developer

Sydney

Responsible for requirements gathering, implementation, and testing of key company projects.

- Maintained and enhanced ICMS, a corporate credit card and expense management software, in regular contact with client services team to gather client requirements and scope
- Implementations of client specific general ledger export plugins
- Mentored new development staff
- Administered and maintained office Linux servers

## Education

University of Wollongong

Feb 2003 - Mar 2006

Bachelor of Computer Science